<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random Forest on Sandeep Gunda</title>
    <link>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/tags/random-forest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random Forest on Sandeep Gunda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sandeepGunda.github.io/tags/random-forest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti Money Laundering</title>
      <link>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/aml/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/aml/</guid>
      <description>Worked with the largest regional bank in the South-East USA which spends a considerable amount of time and resources investigating 30k+ suspicious money laundering alerts per month to develop a model which predicts the seriousness of the alerts. Led a team of 4 and tackled issues such as peer – profiling, unavailable data and false positives by feature generation and selection. Tested the data with Logistic Regression, Random Forest, SVC and ADA Boost models to predict the quality of alert (High or Low) using precision and recall parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flight Departure Delay Prediction</title>
      <link>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/flight-delay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/flight-delay/</guid>
      <description>Obtained the dataset and converted date, month and year columns into date-time object, then into single date column. Encoded Airport and Airline names into numerical labels for easier analysis. Scraped weather data from www.wunderground.com (Weather Underground) and integrated into the flight delay dataset. Split Departure Delay column into 4 bins based on the amount of delay and predicted it using Random Forest, Logistic Regression, Decision Tree and Naïve Bayes from Scikit-learn library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>