<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Scraping on Sandeep Gunda</title>
    <link>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/tags/web-scraping/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Scraping on Sandeep Gunda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sandeepGunda.github.io/tags/web-scraping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sports Team Optimization</title>
      <link>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/sports-team-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/sports-team-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: In Indian Premier League, 11 teams are competing in a round-robin tournament. Before the tournament, there is an auction to buy players based on the fixed budget for each team, with some limitation on the number of foreign players per team, number of uncapped players per team, etc. In IPL, the franchise managers have a task of building a good team within the budget cap. The players are usually selected based on different heuristics, past experiences, or at most some crude methodologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison between Customer Reviews and Business Ratings</title>
      <link>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/comparison-ratings-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/comparison-ratings-reviews/</guid>
      <description>Work Performed:
 Extracted information and reviews for 200 hotels on Expedia by web-scraping in Python. Designed a SQL database for hotel information using normalized Entity Relationship model. Calculated the sentiment for customer reviews using Semantria for Excel and designed a Mongo DB database for the sentiments. Compared the sentiments with the hotel ratimngs for various categories.  Conclusion:
 Even though most of the hotels have a similar User Rating and Expedia Rating, the sentiments of the reviews often differ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flight Departure Delay Prediction</title>
      <link>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/flight-delay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sandeepGunda.github.io/project/flight-delay/</guid>
      <description>Obtained the dataset and converted date, month and year columns into date-time object, then into single date column. Encoded Airport and Airline names into numerical labels for easier analysis. Scraped weather data from www.wunderground.com (Weather Underground) and integrated into the flight delay dataset. Split Departure Delay column into 4 bins based on the amount of delay and predicted it using Random Forest, Logistic Regression, Decision Tree and Naïve Bayes from Scikit-learn library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>